(新八)いや～ ｱﾆﾒ 『銀魂』２年目も
ついに 折り返し｡
GinTama the anime, year two, has reached the halfway point.
いよいよ 次回から
後半戦に突入ですね｡
From the next episode on, we're headed into the second half.
(銀時)なんとか
半年で 打ち切られずに済んだな｡
We somehow managed to avoid getting cancelled after half a year.
(神楽)案ずるより
生むができちゃった婚ｱﾙ！
Don't worry. Have the baby and the shotgun wedding will come.
いやいや ｵﾚたちの
ﾃｺ入れの成果だよ｡
No, no, it was because of our efforts to "boost up" the program.
何 言ってんすか！
あの ﾃｺ入れのおかげで➡
What're you talking about?!
Thanks to us "boosting up" the program,
各方面から怒られまくって➡
we received angry complaints from all over that nearly put an end to the show!
あやうく 逆に番組が終わりそうに
なったんじゃないっすか！
そうだっけ？ まぁ なんにせよ
何もしないより➡
Was that how it was?
Well, at any rate, it's always better to take things on rather than doing nothing.
ﾁｬﾚﾝｼﾞすることが大事だって
ゆとり教育でも習ったろ？
We learned that from our pressure-free education.
(神楽)そうね｡
おけつに入らずんば 痔も得ずｱﾙ｡
Right. You can't get hemorrhoids if you never enter the anus.
[Note: Spoof of "Unless you enter the tiger's den, you cannot steal her cubs."]
間違ってるよ！ 虎穴だよ！
痔も得ずってなんだよ！
You've got that all wrong! It's "If you never enter the tiger's den"!
What do you mean by "can't get hemorrhoids"?!  Who even wants that?!
いらないよ そんなもの！
とにかく これからの 『銀魂』も➡
Anyway, what we're trying to say is that GinTama will keep on truckin'!
ｶﾞﾝｶﾞﾝいくぜ！ ってこった｡
(神楽)さぁ 今日は 何の話ｱﾙか？
So then, what's today's story?
銀さん 今日も暴れちゃうよ～！
いや… それがですね…➡
Gin-san's going to work really hard!
Well, it seems we've already used up half the year's production budget...
実は 半年分の制作費を前回までで
使い切っちゃったらしくて…｡
(神楽)なんだと～！
使い込みｱﾙか!?
What?! Was it embezzled?!
それとも
ｸﾞﾘﾝﾋﾟｱでも建てたか この野郎！
Or did they build a Greenpia, you bastards?!
[Note: Many Greenpia health resorts were built in Japan as part of a huge government embezzlement scam.]
建てるか そんなもん！
いや～ ｽﾀｯﾌがね➡
We wouldn't build such a thing!
The staff worked really hard and seems to have gone over budget.
ちょっと がんばっちゃったら➡
なんかね
予算ｵｰﾊﾞｰしちゃったみたいでね…｡
Nothing we can do about that. We barely have enough production funds as it is.
しようがねえな～｡
まぁ 制作費 ｶﾂｶﾂだしな｡
(神楽)もっと 予算くれよ
この野郎！
Give us a bigger budget, dammit.
せめて ××の半分でいいから
くれよ ｻﾝﾗｲｽﾞ｡
Even half of what (beep) gets would be good, Sunrise.
[Note: GUNDAM covered by "beep" sound. Sunrise Inc. is GinTama's production studio.]
どさくさにまぎれて
何 言ってんの！
What're you saying in the midst of this mess? Who're you speaking for?
ｱﾝﾀら 誰の代弁者!?
仕事のｸﾞﾁは 家でこぼさず➡
Didn't someone say, "Don't complain about your job at home, do it somewhere else"?
外でこぼせって
誰かも言ってたじゃん｡
知りませんよ そんな格言｡
だけど 本当に 今日の放送➡
I wouldn't know! But seriously, what're we going to do about today's broadcast?
どうしましょう？
まぁ そんなときは あれだ｡
Well, when the time comes,
寄せ集めの総集編で
お茶をにごすんだよ｡
we can patch together a recap episode and avoid the whole issue.
(神楽)新作ｶｯﾄの２つ３つ
入れとけば ﾔﾂら全員 騙せるｱﾙ｡
If we include two or three new scenes, we can fool everyone.
なに このﾃﾞｼﾞｬﾌﾞな感じ…｡
いったい どうなるんだ➡
What's with this déjà vu idea?
What's going to happen on today's GinTama?
今日の 『銀魂』は…!?
とりあえず いったん ＣＭです｡
For now, let's cut to a commercial.
[As it does every half season, today's GinTama special begins with only background info. The once every half-season background info only.]
[What makes this a special? It's ??? special and XXX special.]
♪♪～
(新八)あぁ いつ聴いても
いい曲だな～ ﾎﾝﾄ｡
It's such a great song, no matter how many times I hear it.
(銀時)つぅか 何？ これ｡
え？ お通ちゃんのﾃﾞﾋﾞｭｰ曲➡
What was that?
Otsu-chan's debut song, "Your Mother is Chome-Chome."
『お前の母ちゃん××だ』ですよ｡
そうじゃねえよ！
That's not what I meant.
(神楽)『銀魂』のｵｰﾌﾟﾆﾝｸﾞ
こんなんじゃなかったｱﾙ！
That wasn't the GinTama opening number.
いや～ こっちのほうが
『銀魂』に合ってるかな～って｡
No, I think this song matches GinTama better.
合ってねえよ！ この ｱｲﾄﾞﾙｵﾀｸが！
No, it doesn't, you pop idol otaku!
だいたい ｵｰﾌﾟﾆﾝｸﾞとか ｴﾝﾃﾞｨﾝｸﾞとか
ｽﾎﾟﾝｻｰと ﾀｲｱｯﾌﾟなんだから➡
In the first place, the opening and closing songs are tie-ups with the sponsors,
勝手に変えたら 怒られんだよ｡
ﾑｰさんのｸﾋﾞが とんじゃうよ!?
so we'll be scolded if we change it on our own! Mu-san will be fired!
ﾑｰさんって誰だよ…｡
Who's Mu-san? Okay, I get it. We'll do it the right way.
わかりましたよ
ちゃんと やりますよ｡
それじゃあ 改めまして➡
Okay, once more, we'll play redballoon's "Gin Iro no Sora." Okay...
[Note: Song title translated is "Silver-Colored Sky."]
redballoonさんで
『銀色の空』です｡ どうぞ｡
♪♪～
って ｵｰｲ!! これ なんか
変なの交じってるよ！ 何これ！
Hey! There was something weird mixed in there! What's going on?!
(ﾊﾀ皇子)変なのではない
ﾊﾀ皇子じゃ｡
I'm not something weird. I'm Prince Hata.
何 万事屋ﾌｧﾐﾘｰみたいな顔して
ｵｰﾌﾟﾆﾝｸﾞに交ざってんだよ！
Why're you in there as if you're a part of the Odd Jobs family?
だいたい
redballoonさんに失礼だろ！
That's an insult to redballoon.
いや この番組の顔といったら
余であろう｡
No, the face of this show would have to be me.
And the theme song should be "Love and Peace."
そして ﾃｰﾏは ﾗﾌﾞ･ｱﾝﾄﾞ･ﾋﾟｰ…｡
うるさい！
無に帰れ！
What're you talking about?! Get lost!!
(ﾊﾀ皇子)あぁ～っ！
あぁ… 気持いい…｡
That feels so good...
とんだ ｼﾞｬﾏが入ったな｡
じゃあ 改めて仕切り直しだ｡
That was a terrible annoyance. Okay then, let's start again. Let's go!
いくぜ！
ｱﾆﾒ２年目 なんとか無事に
折り返し記念！
Celebrating us safely making it to the halfway point of year two!
あんなこと
こんなことあったｱﾙね！
Lots of things happened during that time.
総集編っていうと また 制作費
削られそうなんで言っちゃﾀﾞﾒだよ｡
Don't call it a recap episode, or they'll take away our production funds!
[Odd Jobs Gin]
(３人)『銀魂 ｽﾍﾟｼｬﾙ』 始まるよ！
The GinTama Special begins now!
[Someone said "Don't Complain About Your Job At Home, Do It Somewhere Else" So let me complain. It's already been a year since this anime, which began with, "Land of the Samurai. The days when our country was called that are long past." A lot of things have happened since then. So I thought, it might be a good to time to look back, but then someone said, "Tsk, a recap episode. Isn't that slacking?" Look, it's hard work putting together an anime, so stop complaining!]
＜侍の国… ﾎﾞｸらの国が
そう呼ばれたのは 今は昔の話＞
"Land of the Samurai." There was a time, long ago, when our country was called by that name.
Yes, that's how it was in the beginning.
あぁ こんなんだったな 最初｡
(神楽)懐かしいｱﾙな！
It brings back memories.
Excuse me, I was reading the narration...
おい ちょっと ちょっと！
これ ﾅﾚｰｼｮﾝ 読んでるんだから!!
Hey, wait a minute. What is that? Notice how there aren't that many Amanto out on the streets lately?
そういえば 最近 あんまり
町に 天人 いなくねえか？
(神楽)いろいろ 設定も
忘れられてるｱﾙ｡
A lot of the original concept was forgotten.
Stop chiming in like that. The scene's going to end...
ﾁｬﾁｬ 入れないでくださいよ！
あぁ… ｱﾊﾞﾝ 終わっちゃう｡
＜ それが ﾎﾞｸらの町 江戸である＞
That was our city, Edo...
(神楽)うわっ！ 新八 転んだ｡
ﾄﾞﾝくさいﾔﾂだな｡
Whoa, Shinpachi tripped.
He's a clumsy guy.
No, it's not that kind of scene. It's the scene where I'm bullied by Amanto.
いや これ
そういうｼｰﾝじゃないから｡
天人に虐げられてるｼｰﾝだからね｡
Wasn't this where you knocked down my parfait because of your clumsiness?
この場合 お前が ﾄﾞﾝくさいから➡
ｵﾚのﾊﾟﾌｪ
ひっくり返しちまったんだろ？
(神楽)そうね｡ だから
新八って いわれるんだよ｡
That's right. That's why you're called Shinpachi.
It's a fine name!
名前 悪くねえだろ！
なんだよ!? この公開いじめは｡
Why're you embarrassing me in public!
でも そのおかげで
ﾎﾞｸたちは出会えたんですよ｡
But because of that, we met each other.
What a waste...that parfait was.
もったいなかったな
あんときのﾊﾟﾌｪ…｡
だから ﾊﾟﾌｪにこだわるな おい！
ん!?
おぉ～！ 出た!! かっこいい!!
自分で言うなよ…｡
There I am! I look great!
Don't say that about yourself!
But back then, you really did look cool, Gin-san.
でも このときの銀さん
ﾎﾝﾄ かっこよかったですよ｡
I never imagined you were such a hopeless guy.
まさか こんなﾀﾞﾒ人間だとは
思わなかったですもん｡
((天人:なんだ!? ｷｻﾏ！
Who the hell are you?!
Strapping on a wooden sword in the age of the Sword Ban!
廃刀令のご時世に
木刀なんぞ ぶらさげおって！
ｷﾞｬｰｷﾞｬｰｷﾞｬｰｷﾞｬｰ やかましいんだよ｡
発情期ですか？ この野郎｡
Blah, blah, blah. Are you in heat or something?
Look at what happened to my chocolate parfait because of your fussing.
見ろ これ ﾃﾒｴらが騒ぐもんだから
ｵﾚのﾁｮｺﾚｰﾄﾊﾟﾌｪが…｡
丸々
こぼれちまったじゃねえか!!))
All of it spilled out!
You seemed so charmingly naïve. The way you said your lines and such.
(神楽)なんか ういういしいよね｡
ｾﾘﾌの言い方とかさぁ｡
Kagura-chan, Kagura-chan, would you mind not talking like that?
神楽ちゃん 神楽ちゃん あの…
素みたいに喋んないでくれる？
なんか 先輩に
ﾀﾞﾒ出しされてるみたいで➡
You sound like my senpai pointing out all my faults.
素で ｲﾔなんですけど…｡
Gin-san, you're acting really cool here,
銀さん なんか かっこよさげに
してますけど このあと➡
but later, you laid the blame on me and ran off.
ﾎﾞｸに ぬれぎぬ 着せて
ﾄﾝｽﾞﾗ ぶっこきますから｡
Well, so what. It's in the past now.
まぁ いいじゃねえの｡
過去のことはさ｡
What do you mean by "in the past"?
過去って なんだよ!?
とらわれるな！
Don't let it bother you so much!
Didn't some Newtype say the same thing?
[Note: Spoof of GUNDAM series.]
どっかのﾆｭｰﾀｲﾌﾟも 言ってたろ？
...but too focused, to be called a thug.
((店長に言っとけ｡
味はよかったぜ))
Tell your manager that it tasted great.
Look out!
(神楽)おぉ～！ 私の登場編ｱﾙよ｡
Oh! There I am!
あ～ぁ こんときは 本当に
死んじまったと思って➡
Yeah.... At the time, I thought you were really dead.
思わず ﾀｲﾑﾏｼｰﾝを探したぜ｡
I went looking for a time machine.
あぁ そうでしたね｡
ﾀｲﾑﾏｼﾝ ﾀｲﾑﾏｼﾝ｡
Yeah, I remember. "Time machine...time machine."
銀さんが 必死になって
探してましたね｡
You were desperately looking for a time machine.
Right, right. This is it. The entranceway into the unknown.
そう そう｡ これだ これ｡ これが
未知なる世界への入り口なんだよ｡
This adult should be ashamed of himself.
みっともないよ この大人…｡
((井上:な… なんだ!?
(ﾔｸｻﾞ)何が起きた!?
Wh-What's this?
What happened?!
(神楽)私… 戦うの 好き｡
I like to fight.
それ 夜兎の本能…))
That is a Yato's true nature.
Huh? Kagura-chan, Don't you think you looked more mature back then?
あれ？ 神楽ちゃん
こんときのほうが➡
大人っぽくない？
あぁ そういえば➡
Now that you mention it, she seems to be regressing lately.
最近 どんどん
退行してる感じがするぞ｡
What're you saying? A woman always wants to remain youthful.
(神楽)何 言ってるね！ 女は
いつも 若くありたいものね｡
You're not youthful-you're just a kid.
若いんじゃねえよ｡ ｶﾞｷなんだよ｡
Should we just drag on and on with commentary like this today?
っていうか
今日 こんな ｺﾒﾝﾀﾘｰ的な感じで➡
だらだらしてて いいんですかね？
えっ!?
What? Didn't you say we should reminisce?
だって 振り返ろうって言ったろ？
(神楽)結構 楽しいｱﾙ｡ 楽だし｡
It's a lot of fun, and it's easy, too.
Don't call it easy.
楽とか 言うなよ！
でも このﾍﾟｰｽで やってたら➡
But if we continue at this pace, it'll take quite a long time to cover a year-and-a-half.
１年半分 振り返るのに
相当 時間 かかるんですけど｡
しようがねえな｡ じゃ １年目は
歌にのせて ぱっぱと振り返るぜ｡
Can't be helped. Then let's do a quick overview of the first year to a song.
♪♪～
後半は
もっと真面目にやりま～す！
We'll take the second half a lot more seriously!
(神楽)ＣＭのあとに 重大発表！
We have an important announcement after the commercial!
ｽﾃｲﾁｭｰﾝ ﾁｬﾝﾈﾙは そのまま！
Stay tuned. Don't change that channel!
っていうか
ないからね なんにも｡
But there isn't anything.
重大発表とか
ｳｿでつるの やめなさい ﾎﾝﾄ｡
Stop leading them on by saying there's an important announcement.
[Encore: Sorachi's Musings 1]
(空知)夢は木と似ています｡
"Dreams are like trees. They're more fun to climb than to just gaze at."
眺めるより 登ったほうが楽しい｡
登って
初めて わかることもあるし｡
"There are things you'll learn only when you actually climb after them."
ｵﾚって 意外と汗かき｡
Like: "I sweat a lot."
[Encore: Sorachi's Musings 2]
つけﾍﾟﾝ使うの めんどくせえよ｡
"Man, fountain pens are a pain to use.
背景描くのも めんどくせえし｡
It's difficult to draw backgrounds and man, drawing manga is hard...
ﾎﾝﾄめんどくせえな
漫画描くのって｡
っていうか もう生きることが
めんどくさい｡
Which means just living is a pain, too..."
ﾁｰｽﾞ蒸しﾊﾟﾝになりたい｡
"I want to become a steamed cheese roll."
[Preview]
♪♪～
[Finally...for our eager fans...]
[a movie version!]
[That sword...]
(桂)ｷｻﾏ その刀…！
Damn, That sword...
(似蔵)ﾔﾂを斬ったのは
ｵﾚじゃない｡
[Is said to drink human blood.]
But I wasn't the one who killed him.
なぁ 紅桜よ｡
Right, Benizakura?
♪♪～
[GinTama The Movie - Benizakura Arc]
[Gintoki in peril]
(似蔵)ﾌﾝ！
銀さ～ん!!
Gin-san!!
[They are called...]
(また子)この 来島 また子の
早撃ちに 勝てると思ってんすか！
You think you can win against Matako Kijima quick-draw?
[Kiheitai]
(武市)ﾛﾘｺﾝじゃない ﾌｪﾆﾐｽﾄです｡
I don't have a Lolita complex. I'm a feminist.
(志士)なんだ この小娘！
What the hell kind of girl is she?!
うっ！
(銃声)
[Hurry, go now!]
ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ先輩！
Elizabeth Senpai!
[Shinsuke Takasugi returns]
(高杉)
二度と ｵﾚたちを➡
Don't ever call Gintoki my chum again.
同志なんて
呼び方するんじゃねえ｡
そんな 甘っちょろいもんじゃ
ねえんだよ ｵﾚたちは｡
There're no warm feelings between us anymore.
(桂)いつから違った？
ｵﾚたちの道は｡
When did it all begin? When did our paths diverge?
[They shared the same beginnings...]
(高杉)ﾌﾝ 確かに ｵﾚたちは➡
It's true that the two of us started in the same place.
はじまりこそ
同じ場所だったかもしれねえ｡
だが あの頃から ｵﾚたちは
同じ場所など見ちゃいねえ｡
But even back then we were heading in different directions.
[Original story by Hideaki Sorachi
(serialized in Weekly Shonen Jump)]
♪♪～
[The universe's dumbest samurai!]
In the midst of an extreme fight to the death...
(鉄矢)あれは
極限の命のやりとりのなかで➡
体の奥に眠る
戦いの記憶が甦ったのか!?
have the memories of past battles lying dormant deep inside his body been awakened?
♪♪～
[The excitement is reborn on the big screen!]
(つんぽ)あれが 坂田 銀時と
桂 小太郎…｡
So they're Gintoki Sakata and Kotaro Katsura...
(つんぽ)強い｡ 一手
死合うてもらいたいものだな｡
They're strong... I'd like to face them someday.
(桂)高杉！
Takasugi!
(２人)全力で ﾃﾒｴをぶった切る！
We'll cut you down...with every ounce of our strength!
[Opening March 2008 During Spring Break!
Also showing: Ninth Grade Class Z Ginpachi Sensei]
I told you, stop attracting viewers with a fake trailer!
だから ｳｿでつるの やめなさい
って言ったでしょ！
信じる人いたら どうすんの!?
What if someone actually believed that?!
嘘から出たまことちゃん
ってことも あるじゃん｡
Sometimes there's truth in lies!
ひょっとして
これを きっかけに➡
Maybe this will kick off an actual movie!
ﾏｼﾞに 映画とか
あるかもしれねえだろ｡
ｻﾝﾗｲｽﾞお得意の再編集映画ね｡
One of those "re-edited movies" that Sunrise is known for.
ﾃﾚﾋﾞでは観られなかった
新たなｼｰﾝが！
If we say there are scenes that weren't seen on TV, we can fool them.
…とか言えば
ﾔﾂら みんな騙せるｱﾙ！
騙して どうすんだよ！
What good would fooling them do?!
じゃあ 次は 紅桜編で
神楽ちゃんが➡
Next, we'll start with the scene in the Benizakura Arc
高杉 晋助と遭遇する
このｼｰﾝから｡
where Kagura-chan meets Shinsuke Takasugi.
おい お前 この船の船員ｱﾙか？
Hey, are you a part of this ship's crew?
ちょいと
中 案内してもらおうか｡
Could you show me around?
頭 ぶち抜かれたくなかったらな｡
Unless you want me to make your head go pop.
(神楽)おい 聞いてんのか｡
Hey, you hear me?
(ﾊﾀ皇子)今日は また ずいぶんと
でけぇ月が出てんな｡
There's a large moon out tonight.
(ﾊﾀ皇子)かぐや姫でも
下りてきそうな夜だと思ったが➡
I thought moon Princess Kaguya might come down tonight...
とんだ じゃじゃ馬姫が
下りてきたもんだ｡
But Princess Tomboy showed up instead.
ｳﾌﾌ｡
《やばい… ｺｲﾂ やばい！
っていうか…》
This is bad. This guy smells dangerous.
But...
(銀時たち)なんで お前が
ｱﾌﾚｺしてんだよ!!
Why're you dubbing his voice?!
いやぁ 余も一度は
ｱﾌﾚｺしてみたかったのだ｡
Well, I wanted to do it just this once.
全国の高杉ﾌｧﾝに 殺されますよ!!
Takasugi fans around the country are going to kill you!
でも なんか
すげえ おもしろくねえ？
But didn't you think it was awfully funny?
Shall we do it on other scenes, too?
他のｼｰﾝでも やってみるか｡
え ﾏｼﾞですか？
余に任せるのじゃ｡
What?! Are you serious?!
Leave it to me.
高杉｡
じいさん けしかけたの お前か？
Takasugi, are you the one who egged on the old man?
(ﾊﾀ皇子)けしかける？
ﾊﾞｶ言うな｡
Egged him on? Don't be ridiculous.
立派な牙が見えたんで
研いでやっただけの話よ｡
His fangs were already showing. I just polished them.
わかるんだよ… ｵﾚも
あのじいさんの 苦しみが｡
You see, I know the suffering that old man is going through.
ｵﾚの中でも いまだ➡
There still remains a black beast of vengeance inside of me, as well.
黒い獣が
のた打ち回ってるもんでな｡
(ﾊﾀ皇子)仲間の仇を…
ﾔﾂらに 同じ苦しみを！
Thrashing about all day and all night, saying in my ear:
殺せ 殺せ！ と耳元で
四六時中…｡
"Kill. Kill the enemies of my friends. Make them suffer the way we suffered."
で 銀時 ﾃﾒｴには
聞こえねえのか？
Gintoki, can't you hear those voices? No, I suppose you can't.
いや… 聞こえるわけねえよな｡
(笑い声)
殺される…
絶対 殺される｡
They're going to kill you. They're definitely going to kill you.
ﾗﾌﾞ･ｱﾝﾄﾞ･ﾋﾟｰｽじゃ｡
Love and Peace.
(ﾊﾀ皇子)桂だ｡
天人！
It's Katsura.
Amanto?!
(ﾊﾀ皇子)ﾂﾞﾗ 聞いたぜ お前さん
以前 銀時と一緒に➡
Zura, I've heard about you.
That you and Gintoki beat up the Harusame.
あの春雨相手に
やらかしたらしいじゃねえか｡
ｵﾚはね 連中と手を結んで
後ろ盾得られねえか➡
I was trying to link up with them to gain their backing.
苦心してたんだが おかげで
うまく ことが運びそうだ｡
But thanks to you, I think it'll go well. When I present them with your head.
お前たちの首を手土産にな｡
高杉！
(ﾊﾀ皇子)言ったはずだ｡
Takasugi!
I told you... I will destroy this rotten world.
ｵﾚは ただ 壊すだけだ｡
この腐った世界を!!
(笑い声)
(ﾊﾀ皇子)ｷﾞｬｰ!!
いい加減にしろや～!!
That's enough!
ﾁｪｰ おもしろかったのに｡
But it was fun...
よし 銀さんも やっちゃうよ～｡
Okay, I'll join in, too.
あ～んなの
ｼﾞｭｰｽと一緒ですことよ｡
That stuff's like juice.
腹を切れ！
Commit seppuku.
ﾁｨ… 私も ﾆｭｰﾀｲﾌﾟなはずだ！
I'm also a Newtype!
うわぁ！
じゃあ 私も やってみるｱﾙ！
Wow! Let me try!
(神楽)坂田さ～ん｡
うわっ じゃ… ﾎﾞｸも！
Sakata-san.
Then me, too.
ﾀﾞﾝﾅ ﾐﾝﾄﾝしましょうよ！
Boss, let's play badminton...
って なんだこりゃ
やってる場合か～!!
What am I doing? I can't be doing this!
Okay, now we'll move on to the Shinsengumi Arc.
じゃあ ここからは 真選組編です｡
Watch it with Otsu-chan's song.
お通ちゃんの曲にのせて どうぞ！
(お通)
それじゃ １曲聴いてください！
Okay, then, listen to this song! "Chome-ko Nanza Kuso Kurae!"
『ﾁｮﾒ公なんざ ｸｿくらえ！』
♪♪～
(近藤)
ﾄｼ やっぱ呼んでよかったﾅﾎﾟﾘﾀﾝ｡
Toshi, I'm glad we invited her, after all. Neapolitan.
(土方)
んなわけねえだろｯｷｰⅢ炎の友情｡
Hell no! Rocky III "The Flames of Friendship"!
♪♪～
And that's it. Did you enjoy today's GinTama?
というわけで
お送りしました 今日の『銀魂』｡
いかがだったでしょう？
(神楽)ｸﾞﾀﾞｸﾞﾀﾞだったｱﾙ｡
I'm really beat.
That was very GinTama-like, so I'm cool with it.
まぁ それも『銀魂』らしくて
いいんじゃね？
After the closing theme,
ｴﾝﾃﾞｨﾝｸﾞのあとは 次回からの
柳生編の予告もあります｡
there's a preview of the Yagyu Arc that begins in the next episode.
お見逃しなく
それでは また来週～！
Don't miss it. Well then, we'll see you next week! Please watch!
観てください！
(神楽)ばいちゃ！
Bye!
[Note: Spoof of DR. SLUMP. Ending phrase by Arale.]
I don't even know what'll happen two days from now.
[Note: Spoof of Armored Trooper VOTOMS ending phrase.]
あさって そんな先のことは
わからない｡
♪♪～
[The name is...]
[Kyubei Yagyu.]
I am Kyubei Yagyu.
Oh my god...
[Otae's fiancé...]
There's a huge gorilla in here!
[suddently appears.]
I missed you...
Now it's your turn to keep your promise, Tae-chan.
Everyone... Farewell...
We are the guardians of the Yagyu family.
[Yagyu versus Kodokan]
[Itsuki Kitaoji]
Itsuki Kitaoji.
[Sui Minamito]
Sui Minamido.
[Tsukamu Nishino]
Tsukamu Nishino.
[Ayumu Tojo]
And, Ayumu Tojo.
[Can Gintoki and friends win against the Four Yagyu Aces?]
You face the Four Yagyu Aces, don't even think about leaving here alive.
["In Those Situations, Keep Quiet and Cook Red Rice With Beans"]
[Otae and Kyubei made a promise as children.]
[The "Yagyu Arc" begins, at last, in the next episode!]